Guide to the Dept. of Soil, Crops, and Atmospheric Science records, 1900-1996.
Dept. of Soil, Crops, and Atmospheric Science records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Soil, Crops, and Atmospheric Science records, 1900-1996.
21-13-2078
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Science.
10.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Photographs, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records include a manuscript concerning the history of agronomy at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records include a manuscript concerning the history of agronomy at Cornell University; eleven photograph albums pertaining to soils and crops, taken by Cornell professors E. O. Fippin, E. L. Worthen, Ernest VanAlstine, and others; correspondence and design material for Caldwell and Leland field houses, and Bradfield and Emerson Halls. Also, black and white photographs of department activities, 1950s and 1960s, and portraits of the faculty, 1920-1950. Also, photographic slides and photoprints and negatives (c.1905-1980), especially by Reeshon Feuer and Harry Kerr, of agronomic projects and tests; and Herbert B. Hartwig instructional materials for elementary agronomy.
Also, photographs, many well annotated, of 1930s and 1940s farm structures and equipment, soil conservation; framed print that served as a departmental registry of marriages; photograph of Chinese trainees; slides, and other papers and records.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Science.; Feuer, Reeshon.; Fippin, E. O.; Hartwig, Herbert B.; Kerr, Harry.; VanAlstine, Ernest.; Worthen, E. L.; Cornell University--Buildings.; New York State College of Agriculture--Buildings.; New York State College of Agriculture.Dept. of Agronomy--History.; New York State College of Agriculture.Dept. of Agronomy--Description--Views.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Study and teaching.; Crops and soils.; Soil management.; Agronomy.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Scrapbooks of Farm Landscape - old photos and descriptions, Early 1900s (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks of Farm Landscape - old photos and descriptions, Early 1900s (Box 4)
- Various photos from the 1940s-1960s and Scrapbook, album #10 – created by Ernest VanAlstine, 1937. Includes photos of special interest: County Agent Groups; Virgil Experimental Station; pastures, oxen, tractors and tillage; Michigan trip; Caldwell Field experiments; corn; weeds; soybeans; silage; equipment; reforestation; soil conservation; C.R. Harrington; forage crops; Leo Hayes Scrapbook, album #11 – created by E.L. Worthen, 1936-1940. Includes photos of special interest: Virgil Experimental Field; Caldwell Field Plots; pastures; meeting of American Society of Agronomy; Alfred Forest erosion experiment; Kenwood Sheep Farm., 1930s-1960s (Box 5)
- Framed print of woman with angels with departmental registry of marriages on back, 1936-1944 (Box 5)
- Photos of Dept, faculty (including Hartwig) and a copy of “Agronomy at Cornell 1868-1980” by Marlin Cline, 1982., 1928-1960s (Box 6)
- Annual Reports, 1957-1969; 1951?; 1942-1952; 1957-1959 (Box 7)
- Green Acres Program (Box 7)
- Cornell Feed Service Letter (Box 7)
- Cooperative Grange League Federation Exchange, Inc. (Box 7)
- Agronomy Dept. – Cooperative Extension (Box 7)
- Reeshon Feuer Photo File, 1940s (Box 8-10)
- Photo of Chinese Agricultural Trainees at Cornell (1945-1946); slides of fields and pastures; glass negative of Prof. J.K. Wilson; photos of Professors Norah Johnston Wallace, MacDonald and Boutflour and various experiment stations., 1930s-1940s (Box 15)
- Various negatives, including Boyce Farm Pond, Weir Shelter, Arnot Station and pastures., 1930s-1940s (Box 16)
- Agronomy Dept – old photos, glass prints, and slides., Early 1900s (Box 17-18)
- Alphabetical photo file – Harry Kerr – State Committee, 1950s (Box 19-21)
- Agronomy Extension Dept. photos and negatives, Early 1900s (Box 22-24, 2)
- Slides, 1963 Sugar Beet Feasibility Study, Publications by H. B. Hartwig and Hartwig course material., Various Dates (Box 1)
- "An Historical Outline of Soil Investigations in New York State" by John W. Gilmore, 1903 (Box 25)
- "History of Development of Extension Work in Agronomy" by J.H. Barron, 1938 (Box 25)
- Cornell Campus Elms Project - Progress Report, 1938 (Box 25)
- Brief historical summary of Agronomy extension work in New York State, 1934-1939 (Box 25)
- Winter Short Course Development at Cornell by C.A.Taylor, 1939 (Box 25)
- "A Water Quality Curriculum for the Northeast Region - Using Distance Learning Methods" - Final Report, 1995 (Box 25)
- "Continuing Education on Nonpoint Source Pollution Prevention Through Regional Networks" - Final Report, 1995 (Box 25)
- Videoconference "Targeting and Prioritizing Quality Problems for Nonpoint Source Pollution Control", 1995 (Box 25)
- "A Water Quality Curriculum Using Distance Learning Methods - Year 2 - Final Report, 1996 (Box 25)
- Videoconference "Watershed '96 On the Air", June 1996 (Box 25)